(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
同じ未来を見ていたい
I want to watch the same future with you
あの夢手にしたい
I want to grasp that dream
それぞれ違った心で
With our different hearts
走れGo!
Run, let's go!
みんな今日、あずき活動4周年ライブ来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you all for coming to AZKi's 4th anniversary live today!
盛り上がっていきましょう！
Let's get fired up!
どこ見ても真っ暗な場所に芽生えてた
It sprouted in a place where everything looked pitch black
ほんの小さな希望にこの瞳奪われた
My eyes were stolen by a tiny bit of hope
不安で揺れる心をうまくチューニングして
Tuning my heart that swayed with anxiety
ほんの小さな勇気を振り絞っていたよ
I was squeezing out a tiny bit of courage
諦めの文字デリートして進む
I delete the word "giving up" and move forward
苦しい時ももう私は
Even when times are tough, I'm no longer...
一人じゃないから
...alone anymore
だからもっと夢追いかけたい
So I want to chase my dreams even more
ワクワク止まらない
The excitement won't stop
想像を超えてく世界見せてあげる
I'll show you a world that goes beyond your imagination
アクセスしてみたい心躍らさせたい
I want to access it, I want to make hearts dance
それぞれ違った心で
With our different hearts
走れGo!
Run, let's go!
仮想の空に輝く眩しい想いは
The dazzling feelings shining in the virtual sky
見たこともない光をリアルに届けるよ
Will deliver a light you've never seen to the real world
いつも聞こえるエールはここにキャッチして
Catching the cheers I always hear right here
また新しい光を探したくなるよ
Makes me want to look for a new light again
君の笑顔は保存して進む
I save your smile and move forward
悲しい時に見返すよ
I'll look back at it when I'm sad
力が湧くから
Because it gives me strength
胸を張って夢追いかけたい
I want to chase my dreams with pride
奇跡のストーリー
A miraculous story
一緒に作ろう終わらない夢を
Let's create a never-ending dream together
誰一人気付かせない鮮やかなこの世界
A vivid world that no one has noticed yet
それぞれ違った心で
With our different hearts
彩れ
Color it in
悲しい時も
Even in sad times
寂しい時も
Even in lonely times
信じ合えるものがある
There's something we can believe in together
忘れずに
Without forgetting
この鼓動 鳴らし続けたい
I want to keep this heartbeat sounding
終わらない世界に
In a world that never ends
溢れ出すよ 笑顔たち
Smiles start to overflow
憧れの舞台立ちたい
I want to stand on the stage of my dreams
正しく輝きたい
I want to shine brightly
時に涙して
Sometimes shedding tears
また笑いあいたい
I want to laugh together again
同じ未来を見たい
I want to see the same future
あの夢 手にしたい
I want to grasp that dream
踏み出そう
Let's step forward
奇跡の一歩を
Towards a miraculous first step
意気出し切って 夢追いかけたい
I want to give it my all and chase my dreams
ワクワク止まらない
The excitement won't stop
ざわざわ越えてく 世界見せてあげる
I'll show you a world that goes beyond the noise
アクセスしてみてない？
Won't you try accessing it?
後悔なんてここにない
There are no regrets here
それぞれ違った
Each of us had different...
心で作るわ
...hearts that we create with
みんな、こあずきー！
Everyone, Ko-AZKi!
本日は、AZKi 活動4周年記念ライブ...
Today, for AZKi's 4th Anniversary Live...
4th Anniversary Live "Pages"にお越しいただき ありがとうございます！
4th Anniversary Live "Pages," thank you so much for coming!
わぁ、コメントもたくさん、ありがとう！
Wow, so many comments, thank you!
お祝いのコメントも、みんなありがとうございます。
Thank you all for the congratulatory comments.
そして、えー、事前にも告知している通り...
And, as announced beforehand...
本日は、えー、新ビジュアルをお披露目します！
today, I'll be revealing my new visual!
ということで、ぜひ最後まで見ていってください！
So please stay with me until the very end!
ということで、1曲目は「Shiny Smily Story (2022 ver.)」をお送りしました。
And so, the first song was "Shiny Smily Story (2022 ver.)".
そしてね、今日はアイドル衣装で今日1曲目、はい、1曲目歌いましたけれども...
And today, I sang the first song in my idol costume...
えっと、何でこの曲を1曲目にしたかというと...
Um, the reason I chose this as the first song is...
えー、AZKi、ホロライブに移籍してからですね、約半年が経ちまして...
it's been about half a year since AZKi transferred to Hololive...
この曲で今日は始めたいと思って歌わせていただきました。
and I wanted to start today with this song.
ということで、もう4周年ですね。
So, it's already the 4th anniversary.
4年ってすごい月日ですね。
Four years is a long time.
だって、これからもう5年目ということで...
I mean, I'm entering my fifth year now...
いやぁ、まさかまさか、こうして今日を迎えられたことに、みんなに感謝したいと。
man, I never expected I'd reach this day like this, and I want to thank everyone.
思います。ありがとうございます。
Thank you so much.
えー、2022年はですね、本当にいろんなことがありました。
2022 was a year where so many things happened.
ちょっと改めてここで振り返ってみますと...
Looking back on it again...
えっと、2021年ですね、12月に、えー、イノナカミュージックのプロジェクトが終了しまして...
um, in December 2021, the Inonaka Music project came to an end...
2022年4月にホロライブに所属することになりました。
and in April 2022, I officially joined Hololive.
もともとAZKiはですね、イノナカミュージックの活動...
Originally, AZKi's Inonaka Music activities...
イコールAZKiのプロジェクト自体がですね、今年の7月に終わるはずだった世界にいたんですけども...
the AZKi project itself, was in a world where it was supposed to end this July...
今日ここで、11月15日、歌っているAZKiがいる...
but here I am on November 15th, an AZKi who is still singing...
世界にみんなに連れてきてもらいました。
everyone brought me to this world.
それが本当によかったのか、悪かったのか、楽しかったのか、楽しくなかったのか、わからないですけれども...
I don't know if that was truly good or bad, fun or not...
でも今日、こうしてコメントでね、応援してくれたりしてくれるみんなが...
but seeing everyone supporting me with comments today...
開拓者のみんながいるんだと、AZKiは今日...
the Pioneers who are here, today AZKi...
もうみんなをすごく、あの、コメントで、あの、感じています。
I can really feel everyone through the comments.
ありがとう。AZKiはだから、ま、今日このライブをやって、やったことで...
Thank you. That's why, by holding this live today...
活動してきてよかったんだなと思ってます。
I feel glad that I've continued my activities.
はい。あの、Vシンガーとしてですね、4年間活動してきて...
Yes. Having performed as a V-singer for four years...
もうこの世界はね、始めたばかりの時は、もう新しくて楽しくて嬉しいことばかりみたいな時もあったんですけど...
in this world, when I first started, there were times when everything felt new, fun, and happy...
4年続けると、あのね、悩んで...
but after four years, you know, I worry...
...たり、悲しいこと、悔しいこともたくさんありました。
...and there were many sad and frustrating times as well.
あの、でもそういう、あの、積み重ねの中で、
But through all those experiences piling up,
えっと、今日はね、新しいスタッフの皆さんにも囲まれて、えー、今日のこのライブができています。
um, today, surrounded by all the new staff members, I'm able to perform this live.
ありがとう。みんながいてくれたからです。ありがとう。
Thank you. It's because you were all here for me. Thank you.
えー、4年間、そして、またこれからですね、
It's been four years, and from here on too,
まあ、いろんな、みんなもね、いろんな出会いと別れを、なんかたくさんあると思うんですけど、
well, I'm sure you all go through many various encounters and partings,
まあその中で、AZKiの歌や音楽がみんなの心に届いたらいいなって思ってます。
but through it all, I hope AZKi's songs and music reach your hearts.
はい、ちょっと真面目な話を、真面目な話をしてちょっと色々思い出したところがありましたけど、
Yes, talking seriously like this brought back a lot of memories,
でも今日は、えー、嬉しいこと、新ビジュアルのお披露目、そして、最後には告知もあるみたいなので、
but today is about happy things, like the new visual reveal and the announcement at the end,
最後まで楽しんでいってください！
so please enjoy yourselves until the very end!
それではちょっとね、アイドル衣装から、いつも着ている普段の衣装にチェンジしたいと思います。
Now, I'm going to change from my idol outfit to the usual outfit I always wear.
さっ。
Ready...
すっ。
...go!
と。ふふ。早着替え、早着替えしてきました。
And... hehe. I did a quick change!
はい。ちょっとお水を飲んでいいですか？お水を飲みます。
Okay. May I have some water? I'm going to take a drink.
はい。ではですね、まあそんな色んな思いを、あの、込めて、今日は歌っていきたいと思います。
Alright. Now then, I'd like to sing today with all those feelings in my heart.
それでは次の曲、聴いてください。
Please listen to the next song.
青い夢。
Blue Dream.
青い夢
Blue Dream
あなたのおかげで私がいる
I am here because of you
聞いてくれたことに価値がある
There is value in the fact that you listened
綺麗事に隠れた本心が
My true feelings, hidden behind fine words
建前の隙間をすり抜けた
Slipped through the cracks of public stance
腫れ物みたいに扱わないで
Don't treat me like I'm something fragile
本心をどうか隠そうとしないで
Please don't try to hide your true feelings
一番欲しいのは誰かのエールか
Is what I want most someone's cheer?
たったそれだけじゃ食いつなぎきれない
Just that alone isn't enough to keep me going
愛が君を救えるなら　音楽はいらないさ
If love could save you, then music wouldn't be needed
夢だけでは私は生き続けられない
I cannot continue to live on dreams alone
誰も間違ってはいないから　正論に押し潰されて
Because no one is wrong, being crushed by sound arguments
息苦しいよ
It's suffocating
弱さを許せば喜ばれてる
Forgiving weakness is appreciated
個性を歌えば支持を得られる
Singing about individuality gains support
なけなしの感情　切り崩して
Whittling away at what little emotion I have left
対価を欲しがることが怖いの
I'm afraid of wanting something in return
一番大事なのは私の想いか
Is what's most important my feelings?
たったそれだけじゃ何も守りきれないよ
Just that alone cannot protect anything
守れないよ
I can't protect it
君変わったねって言われちゃうね　青くなりきれずに
You'll be told you've changed, won't you? Never becoming fully blue
中途半端に大人で嫌になりそうだよ
Being halfway an adult, I'm starting to hate it
愛が君を救えるなら　音楽はいらないさ
If love could save you, then music wouldn't be needed
夢だけでは私は生き続けられない
I cannot continue to live on dreams alone
誰さえない 誰も間違ってはいないから
There is no one, because no one is wrong
せーのに
Ready, set...
押しつぶされて
Crushed by it
でも逃げないよ
But I won't run away
夢だから
Because it's a dream
いのち
作詞・作曲・編曲：瀬名航
Life
Lyrics/Composition/Arrangement: Sena Wataru
息をしている
I am breathing
君は生きている
You are living
当然のこと 誰も疑わないの
It's natural, no one doubts it
息をしている
I am breathing
ように見えている
Or so I look
生の裏側 私にとっての何か
The other side of life, something meant for me
鼓動がドクドクしている
My heart is thumping
叩かれても腐らずに
Without rotting even if I'm beaten down
此処で歌うよ
I will sing here
ボタン一つの いのち
A life within a single button
最後まで私のこと 覚えててくれるの？
Will you remember me until the end?
消えてしまいそうなの 分かってよ 分かってよ ねえ
I feel like I'm about to disappear, understand me, please understand
本当のことなの 恋と愛は違うんでしょ？
It's the truth, love and affection are different, right?
君が忘れちゃったら 私は いなくなるの
If you forget me, I will be gone
いのちのような 夢を見てるよ
I'm having a dream that feels like life
またね バイバイ
See you again, bye-bye
息をしている
I am breathing
だから生きている
That's why I am living
自己証明を欲しがって 欲しがっているんだ
I'm yearning, yearning for self-justification
音が止まって
When the sound stops
動かなくなって
And I stop moving
そんな私を 君は笑ってくれるかな？
Will you smile at me like that?
鼓動がドクドクしている
My heart is thumping
嫌われても腐らずに
Without rotting even if I'm hated
此処で歌うよ
I will sing here
気分次第の いのち
A life depending on my mood
最後まで私のこと 抱きしめてくれるの？
Will you hold me until the end?
冷めてしまいそうなの 分かってよ 分かってよ ねえ
I feel like I'm growing cold, understand me, please understand
声が聞こえるんだよ 塩辛い涙が出ちゃうぞ
I can hear your voice, salty tears are about to come out
君が忘れちゃったら 私は いなくなるの
If you forget me, I will be gone
いのちのような 夢を見てるよ
I'm having a dream that feels like life
またね バイバイ
See you again, bye-bye
ふさぎこんだあの日を
The day I was depressed
軽くイジらないで やめて
Don't make light of it, stop
それが生きる糧になるから
Because that becomes my strength to live
大丈夫 ずっと私は
It's okay, I will always
歌い続けるから
keep on singing
最後まで私は 生きているか分からないけど
I don't know if I'll be alive until the end, but
君がくれた言葉は 確かに残ってる
The words you gave me certainly remain
最後まで私のこと 覚えててくれるの？
Will you remember me until the end?
いつ死んでしまうだろう わかんない わかんないよ ねえ
I wonder when I'll die, I don't know, I just don't know
痛いくらい気持ちが シンクロする時もあるけど
There are times when our feelings synchronize to the point of pain
君が忘れちゃったら 私は いなくなるの
If you forget me, I will be gone
いのちのような 夢を見てるよ
I'm having a dream that feels like life
またね バイバイ
See you again, bye-bye
次の曲はオーバーライトです。
The next song is Overlight.
みんなが連れてきてくれた世界、
The world everyone brought me to,
一緒に楽しみましょう！
let's enjoy it together!
ハイ！ハイ！
Hey! Hey!
そう　見つけた
Yes, I found it
この先だけの世界を
the world that lies ahead
止まりかけていた時を進めるための
to keep moving the time that was about to stop
こんなはずじゃなかった
It wasn't supposed to be like this
ふと漏れた言葉伝え
I convey the words that accidentally spilled out
あの日もよかったと思える君がいるよ
You are here, making me think that day was good too
消えかけても
Even if it fades,
見えなくても
even if it's invisible,
ここには私がいる
I am here
暗闇の世界さえ越えていく光を
A light that will cross even the world of darkness
間違っても
Even if I'm wrong,
無くなっても
even if it's gone,
僕の選ぶ世界
the world I choose
思い描いた花じゃなくたって　この手で咲かすよ
Even if it's not the flower I envisioned, I'll make it bloom with these hands
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！声頂戴！
Hey! Hey! Hey! Let me hear your voices!
あぁ　見つけた
Ah, I found it
無くしかけてた僕の座標
my coordinates that I was losing
エンドロールには早すぎると気づいた
I realized it's too early for the end credits
僕だけじゃないんだ　気づけばそばにいたんだ
It's not just me, I realized you were by my side
足跡は続く
The footprints continue,
ほら聞こえる次の音が
look, I can hear the next sound
届かなくても
Even if I can't reach,
憧れの背に少しだけ追いついた
I've caught up a little to the back of my longing
花と咲くその日まで思いを歌うよ
Until the day it blooms as a flower, I will sing my feelings
遠い糸もまた繋がるそんな世界があるよ
Even distant threads will connect again, there's such a world
次の夜空に光る星々に希望を託そう
Let's entrust our hopes to the stars shining in the next night sky
こんな世界
Such a world,
こんな未来
such a future,
僕らの地図になかった
wasn't on our map
約束できないよ
I can't promise you
こんな素敵な未来
such a wonderful future
想像できないから
because I can't imagine it
消えかけても
Even if it fades,
見えなくても
even if it's invisible,
何度挫けても
no matter how many times I falter
足跡の伸びる先
Ahead of where the footprints stretch,
未来が続くよ
the future continues
そう間違っても
Yes, even if we're wrong,
無くなっても
even if it's gone,
何度でも作ろう
let's create it again and again
行く先を無くしても
Even if we lose our way,
君となら探せるよ
I can find it if I'm with you
上書きの地図を広げて
Spread out the overwritten map
僕らの世界で
In our world
この夜を明かそうよ
Let's pass this night
苦しまず済むんだア
You won't have to suffer
せめて君を覚える　ココロを　取り戻す
At least regain the heart to remember you
え　どうして　何も言わないの
Eh, why don't you say anything?
偽りの言葉を　捨てて
Cast away those false words
afterglow / 作詞:AZKi / 作曲:AZKi, 中川大二郎 / 編曲:中川大二郎
afterglow / Lyrics: AZKi / Composition: AZKi, Daijiro Nakagawa / Arrangement: Daijiro Nakagawa
もう　行かなくちゃいけない
I must go now
長く遠い道の終わり
The end of a long, distant road
静かに眠ったおでこを合わせて
Pressing our foreheads together as you sleep peacefully
深く息をした
I took a deep breath
見上げた先には　赤い空
Looking up, there's a red sky
きっと同じ空を見ているのかな
I wonder if you're looking at the same sky
胸に残る
Remaining in my heart
あなたの　あなたの　あなたの声が今
Your voice, your voice, your voice now...
今夢に落ちて　夢で覚める
...now falling into a dream and waking up in a dream
あなたの　あなたの　あなたの記憶今
Your memory, your memory, your memory now...
私を置いていく
...leaves me behind
ほら　幸せなことは
Look, the happy things...
すぐに消えてしまう予定
...are destined to vanish soon
あんなに好きだった景色も雲も
The scenery and clouds I loved so much...
色褪せてしまった
...have faded away
今を生きていくこと
Living through the now...
一人ひたすら走ること
...and running alone as hard as I can
私という存在は脆くて
My existence is so fragile...
その足動かない
...that my feet won't move
見上げた先には　灰の空
Looking up, there's a gray sky
ちゃんと色を取り戻せるように
So that I can truly regain the colors
世界の真ん中
In the middle of the world
あなたの　あなたの　あなたの声が今
Your voice, your voice, your voice now...
今　こだましてる
...is echoing now
あなたの　あなたの　あなたの欠片今
Your fragments, your fragments, your fragments now...
今　私は探してる
...I am searching for them now
胸に残る
Remaining in my heart
あなたの　あなたの　あなたの声が今
Your voice, your voice, your voice now...
今空に溶けていく
...is melting into the sky now
あなたの　あなたの　あなたの記憶今
Your memory, your memory, your memory now...
今　私を忘れていく
...is forgetting me now
きっとよかった
It was surely for the best
これで最後
This is the end
最後...
The end...
もう一回だ...
One more time...
夢が終わる
The dream ends
てことで、青い夢、いのち、オーバーライト、アフターグロウ、お送りしました！
And so, I presented Aoi Yume, Inochi, Overwrite, and Afterglow!
そして皆さん、お待たせしました。AZKi新ビジュアルお披露目です！
And everyone, thank you for waiting. It's time to reveal AZKi's new visual!
いかがでしょうか？いかがでしょうか？いかがでしょうか？
How do you like it? How do you like it? How do you like it?
あ、たくさん拍手ありがとう！
Ah, thank you for all the applause!
はい、そして衣装チェンジのタイミングで、これまでの、えー、1st, 2nd, 3rdの衣装までの軌跡をまとめた映像も作っていただきまして、
Yes, and during the costume change, a video summarizing the journey through the 1st, 2nd, and 3rd costumes was also made for you.
どうでしたか？なんか、うるっと来ましたね。
How was it? It was quite moving, wasn't it?
ちょっと涙が出そうになるくらい、すごく素敵に、これまでのAZKiの衣装とかもそうですし、MVがね、
It was so wonderful it almost brought tears to my eyes. Looking back at AZKi's past costumes and the MVs...
後ろにね、あの、流れていたと思うんですけど。
...that I think were playing in the background.
はい、そんな、えー、軌跡を、歴史を経て、今日、えー、新ビジュアルとなりました。
Yes, after that journey and history, here I am today with a new visual.
みんなありがとう！
Thank you, everyone!
はい、じゃあちょっともっと詳しく見てもらいたいなと思うので、ちょっとライブ用のこのマイク、置いてきますね。
Alright, I'd like you to see it in more detail, so I'm going to put down this live performance microphone for a moment.
はい、ということで、えー、今回の、えー、新ビジュアルのコンセプトは、
Okay, so, the concept for this new visual...
ズバリ、アーティストなAZKiです！
...is, quite simply, "Artistic AZKi"!
今までもすごい、あの、攻めた衣装だったり、3rd衣装はすごくね、
Until now, the outfits have been quite bold, and the 3rd costume was very much a...
ステージ衣装という感じに、お仕立てしていただいてたんですけれども。
..."stage outfit," as it was designed to be.
今回は、なんかこう、アーティストな、ちょっと大人びたAZKiということで、
This time, it's an artistic, slightly more mature AZKi.
えー、今回デザインはスコッティさん、そして、モデリングは、えー、我らがパパ、加速パパ、加速サトウさんに、お仕立ていただきました！
The design is by Scotty-san, and the modeling was done by our "Papa," Kasoku-papa, Kasoku Satō-san!
はい、じゃあ細かく、みんな細かく見ていきますか？
Alright, shall we take a closer look at the details?
お披露目だからね！お披露目なのでね！
It's a reveal after all! Since it's a reveal!
はい、まず、えー、髪型変えました！
First of all, I changed my hairstyle!
どうですか？髪型ロングになりましたよ！
How is it? I have long hair now!
ロングといえば1st、1st衣装の時もロングではあったけれど、
Speaking of long hair, I had long hair during the 1st costume too, but...
えー、こういったなんかね、ちょっと編み込みがここね、
...this time there's some braiding here,
ここここここ、編み込みがあって、
right here, there's braiding,
後ろでね、こう結んでおりますけれども、えー、ロングに、なりました！
and it's tied at the back. I've gone for a long look!
いかがですか？ロングのAZKiは。
What do you think of long-haired AZKi?
ロング合ってる？あ、似合ってる？あー、嬉しい！嬉しい！
Does long hair suit me? Oh, it looks good? Ah, I'm so happy! I'm so glad!
そうだね、ちょっと今までショートというか、短い髪型だったので、えー、今回はロングのAZKi。
That's right, since I've had short or shorter hairstyles until now, this time it's long-haired AZKi.
そう、ポニテっぽいね、後ろね、ここね。に、お仕立ていただきまして。
Yeah, it's like a ponytail at the back here. That's how it was made for me.
そして、えー、AZKi今まで結構黒のね、衣装とか、
And, AZKi has often had black costumes, and...
ま、3rd衣装はもうピンク、アイドル！というような衣装だったんですけど、
...the 3rd one was all pink—like an idol! But this time...
今回は白をね、基調として、そう、カメラさんありがとうございます。
...it's based on white. Yes, thank you, cameraman.
えー、白を基調とした、ここが、えっとね、ワンピースっぽくなっておりまして、
It's based on white, and this part here is like a one-piece dress.
そして、えー、ブラウスにね、ここの、ここの、ここのブラウスに、
Then there's the blouse, with a big ribbon right here on the blouse,
おっきいリボン、リボンがついており、
a big ribbon,
ここにちゃんとアクセサリーもついており。
and it even has accessories attached.
そしてね、スカートね、こちら、お、下から、下から。
And then the skirt... oh, from the bottom, from the bottom!
えー、スカートが実は2色、このね、あの、左右非対称なんですよ。
The skirt is actually two colors; it's asymmetrical.
これを何て言うんですか？アシンメトリーって言いますか？
What do you call this? Asymmetry?
えー、こうね、左右が非対称な、実は、あの、色が
Yes, it's asymmetrical on the left and right. Actually, the colors are...
ピンクとちょっとグレーというね、もう2色な、
...pink and a bit of gray—two colors!
あの、ワンピース、スカートに、なっております。はい。
It's a two-tone one-piece skirt. Yes.
そしてそして、えー、そうだね、アクセサリーも紹介しよう！
And also, let me introduce the accessories!
この髪のね、ここはAZKiの、あの、今までの衣装の中にも、
For the hair here, there are colors that I've always wanted to keep as important parts of AZKi's outfits...
あの、ずっと大事に取り入れたい色として、
...as a color I've always wanted to incorporate.
このね、グリーン、グリーンの色と、
This green...
AZKiのこの赤とピンク系のちょっとアクセサリーを、あのね、つけてもらいました、作ってもらいました。
...along with AZKi's red and pink tones, were used for these accessories made for me.
まあ... いいでしょ、いいでしょ
Well... it's good, isn't it?
そう、ちゃんとちゃんと今までのこうモチーフとかもちょっと入れたいなと思って
Yeah, I really wanted to incorporate some of my previous motifs.
こんな感じにアクセサリーを作ってもらいました
So I had them make accessories like this.
そして、そう、なんかちゃんとね、今回は
And, yes, properly this time...
このブレスレットとかも結構... ほら見て！すごいピカピカ
Even this bracelet is quite... Look! It's so shiny.
もう、すごく細かく作ってもらっていて...
They made it in such great detail...
このAZKiのこのヘアアクセサリーと、実は、こう形がね、一緒だったり...
It actually has the same shape as this hair accessory of mine...
細かいところまで作っていただいております
They've made it with attention to even the smallest details.
そして、ネイルもちゃんとしておりますよ
And my nails are done properly too.
おしゃれなネイルもしておりますよ
I have stylish nails too.
ありますよ、ということで、綺麗でしょ？
I have them, so, they're pretty, right?
綺麗！あ、綺麗、綺麗
Pretty! Ah, so pretty, so pretty.
ありがとうございます
Thank you very much.
そしてですね、あとはなんだろう...
And then, what else...
あと紹介... 後ろはね、このお花っぽいヘアアクセサリーとなっております
Anything else to introduce... The back has this flower-like hair accessory.
はい
Yes.
どうですか、みんな！
How is it, everyone?
あ、そうだ。今日言うの忘れてた
Oh, that's right. I forgot to say this today.
この、あの、AZKi新ビジュアルお披露目でみんなスクショを撮って...
With this new visual reveal, everyone, please take screenshots...
スクショを撮ってあげてください。ツイート、ツイートしてください
Please take screenshots and post them. Please tweet, tweet about it.
みんな、なんかしてほしいポーズありますか？
Everyone, is there any pose you want me to do?
ありますか？
Is there?
はい。なんだろう、でもなんかアーティストっぽい感じにね、そう、したいと思っていたんで...
Yes. What should it be... Well, I wanted to have an "artist-like" feel...
アーティストっぽい、アーティストっぽい立ち振舞いってどうなんですかね？
I wonder what kind of behavior is artist-like?
こん... こんな感じ？
Like... Like this?
こんな感じですかね？
Something like this?
こんな感じ？
Like this?
違うな
No, that's not it.
くるっと回る？
Spin around?
くるっと回る？はい、くるっと回りますよ
Spin around? Okay, I'll spin around.
どうですか、どうですか？
How is it, how is it?
はい。あ、みんな『かわいい』
Yes. Oh, everyone's saying "cute."
ありがとうございます。振り向きのポーズか
Thank you. A looking-back pose, huh?
こう？こう？どう？どう？
Like this? Like this? How is it? How is it?
こんな感じどうですか？
How about something like this?
どうですか？
How is it?
いいですか？
Is it good?
振り向きのポーズ...
A looking-back pose...
あ、ありがとう、みんな。パシャパシャ、パシャパシャ、パシャパシャ
Ah, thank you, everyone. *click click click click*
はい、ということで、ちょっともう一つ、ちょっとみんなに見せたいものがありまして
Alright then, there's one more thing I'd like to show everyone.
なんとこのね、ジャケットなんですけれども
It's actually about this jacket...
ちょっと脱げます。脱いできます
I can take it off. I'm going to take it off.
ぬぎぬぎ、ぬぎぬぎ、ぬぎぬぎ、ぬぎぬぎ。そして脱いだAZKiがこちら！
Off it comes, off it comes, off it comes. And here is the de-jacketed AZKi!
はい！実は隠れてました！
Ta-da! It was actually hidden!
こちらにリボンが...
There's a ribbon here...
実はあのね、こうワンピースの、このね、腰のところにリボンをつけていただいておりました！
Actually, you see, they've put a ribbon on the waist of this dress!
かわいい！かわいいでしょ、かわいいでしょ
Cute! It's cute, isn't it? It's cute.
そう、スカート、後ろも見せとこうか。こんな感じ
Yeah, let me show you the back of the skirt too. Like this.
こんな感じになっております。かわいい
It looks like this. Cute.
そう、身軽になった。はい
Yeah, I feel lighter now. Yes.
そして、この素敵なデザインの、皆さん、三面図も入手いたしました！
And, I've also obtained the three-view design sheets for this wonderful design!
こちらです！お、こちらです！
Here they are! Oh, here they are!
なんとスコッティさんが細かいところまでお仕立てしてくださいました！
Scotti-san designed it down to the smallest detail!
あとでね、Twitterにもあげるので、ぜひファンアートとかAZKiアートで描いてもらえたら嬉しいなって思います
I'll upload them to Twitter later, so I'd be happy if you could draw fan art of it.
はい、こんな感じで。いや、細かいところまで結構ね、いろいろスコッティさんと練り練りしながら...
Yes, like this. Well, I worked closely with Scotti-san on the fine details...
今回AZKiもあの、衣装のデザインをちょっと一緒に悩みながら、一緒に考えて、今日はこの衣装ができております
AZKi was also involved in the design this time, and that's how this outfit came to be.
はい、いかがですか？みんな気に入ってくれた？
So, what do you think? Did everyone like it?
はい、ということで、みんな余すところなく見ていただけましたか？AZKiの新衣装
So, was everyone able to see every part of it? AZKi's new outfit.
はい、ということで、この衣装でライブの続きをしていきたいと思いますので...
Alright then, I'd like to continue the live show in this outfit...
ちょっとライブ用のマイクをとってきます
I'm going to go grab my live microphone.
はい、あ、ちょっとジャケットも着てきて...
Okay, ah, I'll put the jacket back on too...
はい、みんなコメントありがとう！
Okay, thanks for the comments, everyone!
はい、ということで、まだまだライブは後半戦ということで...
Alright then, we're heading into the second half of the live show...
それでは、このあとは今年ね、リリースした、AZKiが作詞作曲にも関わった楽曲を今日は歌っていきたいと思います
So, next, I'm going to sing songs released this year that I was involved in writing and composing.
ちょっと待って、水飲む。水飲ませて
Wait a moment, I'm drinking water. Let me drink some water.
こちら。はい、ということで...
Here. Okay, so...
では、今年リリースした曲たちを聴いてもらいたいと思います！
Well then, I hope you enjoy the songs released this year!
それでは聴いてください。
Now, please listen.
ペトリコール。
Petrichor.
君に届け
Reach you
愛してると
That I love you
petrichor
雨の夜に映る君が
You, reflected in the rainy night
何を見ていたか分からない
I don't know what you were looking at
でもね その瞳に
But, you know, in those eyes
映る君は笑ってた
The "you" reflected there was smiling
移ろい季節が
The changing seasons
君を奪い去っても
Even if they take you away
僕らまた...
We will again...
響いてゆけ
Go on resonating
朝焼けの産声
The newborn cry of dawn
未来呼ばれている
The future is calling
こだました記憶と
With the echoing memories
空は紡いでゆく
The sky goes on spinning
君の手のひらまで
All the way to your palm
ほら
Look
もう変わっている
It's already changing
今 過去 手に
Now, the past in hand
自由なんて 自分から
Freedom is something you...
掴んでいくよ
grab for yourself
奪われても
Even if it's taken away
新しく出会えるから
Because we can meet anew
君に届け
Reach you
愛してると
That I love you
ゆらゆら動いた
Swaying, it moved
この心も
This heart too
私はあの子になれなかったんだ
I couldn't become that girl
ゆらゆら風吹く
The wind blows, swaying
連れ去っていく
Taking it away
いいな いいな
How nice, how nice
あたしはさ 何も持ってなかった
I, you know, had nothing
canopus
傾いてる気分を無視した
I ignored my sinking mood
今日も無理してあがっちゃうからな
I'll force myself to rise up again today
でっ、あたし すすめるさ
And so, I can move forward
今すぐに手に入れたいけど
I want to get it right now, but...
お預けかもね
it might be on hold
もしも今
If, right now
叶うなら
It could come true
届けたい
I want to reach you
キラキラ輝いて
Sparkling and shining
あの星みたいに
Like that star
あの子はあたしになれなかったんだ
That girl couldn't become me
キラキラ顔出す
Peeking out, sparkling
いっとう星も
Even the brightest star
そうか そうね
I see, that's right
あなたもさ ずっと一緒だった
You, too, were always together with me
ひらひら変わった
Fluttering, it changed
この心象だ
This is my mental image
私はあの子に
I...
なれなかったんだ
...couldn't become that girl
ひらひら季節を
Fluttering, I'll try...
増やしてみる
...increasing the seasons
そうだ そうだ
That's right, that's right
私はさ
I have...
すべて持っている
...everything
ゆらゆら変わった
Swaying, it changed
この未来色も
This future color too
私はあの子に
I...
なれなかったんだ
...couldn't become that girl
ゆらゆら掴んだ
Swaying, I've grasped...
この運命と
...this fate and...
生きてみたい
...I want to try living
みんなとさ
With everyone
今を離さないように
So as not to let go of "now"
equal
作詞・作曲：AZKi、中川大二郎
編曲：中川大二郎
equal
Lyrics/Composition: AZKi, Daijiro Nakagawa
Arrangement: Daijiro Nakagawa
照らす
Shining
日に
On a day
置き忘れた
Left behind
私
Me
光
Light
残る跡が
There are remaining traces
ある
There are
君はどこにいると言ったの？
Where did you say you were?
私は世界にいると言った
I said I was in the world
過去それさえも見えなかった
I couldn't even see the past
僕がいる意味を言いたいの
I want to say the meaning of my existence
わたしが生きるすべてあげる
I'll give you everything I live for
扉を開く鍵は折れた
The key to open the door broke
わたしが生きるすべてを今
I'll teach you everything...
教えてあげるから
...I live for now
僕らの存在が
Even if our existence
意味を持たなくても
Holds no meaning
明日にあの比へと
I can step into the chain...
連鎖を踏み出せる
...towards that day tomorrow
今聞こえてた
I could hear it now
私ここで歌うこと
The fact that I'm singing here
だからもぉ離さないよ
So I won't let go anymore
それだけが答えだったから
Because that was the only answer
はい、ということで、
Yes, so...
聴いていただいたのは、
...you just heard...
Petrichor、Canopus、equalの
...Petrichor, Canopus, and equal,
3曲でしたー！
...the three songs!
今年はAZKiも作詞作曲を頑張るぞ、ということで、
These are songs AZKi made this year...
作った楽曲たちになります。
...with the goal of working hard on songwriting and composition.
ぜひぜひ、気に入った曲があったら、
If there was a song you liked,
聴いてみてください。
please give it a listen.
ということで、皆さん、
And with that, everyone,
告知がございまーす！
I have an announcement!
この後、21時から、えーAZKi活動4周年記念グッズが発売されます！
At 9 PM tonight, AZKi's 4th anniversary goods will go on sale!
わぁー、すごい綺麗なイラストだ！ということで、内容は、こちらになります！
Wow, what a beautiful illustration! And here are the contents!
はい、えーAZKi EP『Pages』、そしてラバーマット、
Yes, the AZKi EP 'Pages' and the rubber mat,
えー、そしてロゴアクリルキーホルダー、そしてTシャツ、
and then the logo acrylic keychain and T-shirt,
シチュエーションボイスの記念ボイスと特典ボイスもありますけれど、
along with anniversary and bonus situation voices,
以上5つのグッズとボイスのセットになります。
that's the set of 5 goods and voices.
さらに、えーフルセットには、箔押し特製、あ、違う、箔押し複製です。箔押し複製メッセージ入り、
Furthermore, the full set includes a special foil-stamped—no, a foil-replicated message,
チェリ子先生の書き下ろしポストカードが付いております。
on an original postcard by Chelico-sensei.
メッセージは届いてからのお楽しみです。
The message is a surprise for when you receive it.
そして、数量限定にはなりますが、こちらのフルセット、お買い上げいただきますと、
Also, in limited quantities, if you purchase this full set,
えーっと、AZKiの直筆サインが入っております！夏のね、7月の誕生日ぶり、
it will come with AZKi's handwritten signature! It's been since my July birthday in the summer,
えー、AZKi頑張ってサイン書きますので、ぜひぜひご購入してくれたら嬉しいです。
so I'll work hard on the signatures! I'd be so happy if you bought it.
そして、ちょっと気になる皆さん、EPの、はい、こちら内容なんですけれども、
And for those curious about the EP, here are the details.
えーっと、今日のね、ライブタイトルにもなっておりますが、
As it shares its title with today's live,
『Pages』ね、今日のこう今までの歴史を、えーっと、なんだろうな、こうページにしたという意味で、
'Pages' represents turning our history up until today into pages.
今回AZKiの今まで、今年出しました、本日歌唱もしております、
It features my releases from this year that I'm also singing today:
『afterglow』、『petrichor』、『canopus』、『equal』
'afterglow', 'petrichor', 'canopus', and 'equal'.
の4曲と、ボーナストラックの『Creating world (Acoustic Ver.)』、合わせて5曲が収録されています。
Including the bonus track 'Creating world (Acoustic Ver.)', there are 5 songs in total.
内容はですね、こちらの楽曲のCDと、えーっと、ブックレット、歌詞カードが付いております。
The contents include the CD, a booklet, and a lyrics card.
そしてなんと、ブックレットには、ここだけの『equal』暗号解説、暗号があります、『equal』、
And surprisingly, the booklet contains an exclusive explanation of the code in 'equal'!
暗号解説も付いてきます。ということで今日の『Pages』ライブの記念にいかがでしょうか。
An explanation of the code is included. It's the perfect memento of today's 'Pages' live.
よろしくお願いします。
Please check it out.
えー、そして、もちろん単品個別販売もございます。ラバーマットはこちら、
Of course, individual items are also available. Here's the rubber mat,
EPやポストカードと同じく、チェリ子先生の書き下ろし、可愛い！
featuring another cute original illustration by Chelico-sensei, just like the EP and postcard!
実はこの今までのAZKiのね、あの1st、2nd、3rdの衣装と、あとあのアイドル衣装のAZKiがなんと散りばめられております。
Actually, it features illustrations of AZKi in my 1st, 2nd, 3rd, and idol costumes.
はい、そしてTシャツはフリーサイズで着やすいものとなっております。
Next, the T-shirt is a comfortable, free-size fit.
AZKiがちょっと黒地にこのAZKiのロゴがいい感じになっているデザインをちょっと選ばせていただきました。
I chose a design where the AZKi logo looks great against the black fabric.
はい、ということで、そして次、ロゴアクリルキーホルダーということで、
Alright, next up is the logo acrylic keychain.
AZKiのロゴもなんという新しくなりました！この衣装に合わせて作っていただきました。
The AZKi logo has been updated! It was designed to match this new costume.
約10センチぐらいの大きさなので、ちょうど手のひらいっぱい大きめサイズです。
It's about 10 cm, so it's a nice, palm-sized large keychain.
ぜひぜひ付けていただけたら嬉しいです。
I hope you'll use it!
というわけで、AZKi活動4周年記念グッズ、この後21時から、
So, AZKi's 4th anniversary goods will be available from 9 PM.
概要欄にも貼りますので、ぜひぜひよろしくお願いいたします。
The link is in the description!
はぁー、ということで、えー、なんと告知も終わりまして、
Whew... And with that, I've finished the announcements.
楽しい時間は早いもので、えー、次の曲で、最後になります。はい。
How time flies when we're having fun... The next song will be the last one.
今日はですね、みんな、AZKiと11月15日、
Everyone, I started my activities on November 15th,
2018年の11月15日に活動始めて今日2022年の11月15日、
back in 2018, and today is November 15th, 2022.
丸4周年ですね。AZKiと一緒に、えーっと, 4周年を迎えてくれて本当に本当にありがとうございます。
It's been exactly four years. Thank you all so very much for celebrating this milestone with me.
みんながこうやって応援してくれるから、今日AZKiはこのステージに立ってますし、
I'm standing on this stage today because of all your support,
新ビジュアルという素敵なね、あの衣装とそしてこのね、もう素敵な、あのものをいただいてしまいました。
and I've been given this wonderful new visual and outfit.
本当にみんなが、あのー、なんかいっぱい、色々くじけそうになったこともたくさんあるんですけど、
Truly, there were many times when things felt tough and I almost lost heart,
でもそれでも、えーっと、ホロライブに来て、こうやって温かく迎えてもらって、
but even so, I came to Hololive and was welcomed so warmly.
あのー、歌を歌ったり、音楽を作ったり、これからも頑張っていきたいと思っておりますので、
I want to keep singing and making music, and I'll continue to do my best.
これからも5年目も、明日から5年目ですね、
So please keep supporting me in my fifth year, starting tomorrow!
5年目もどうぞ応援よろしくお願いします。本当にありがとうございます。
Thank you so much.
ということで、最後の曲聴いてください。
With that, please listen to the last song.
Creating world アコースティックバージョン。
Creating world (Acoustic Ver.)
作詞・作曲：流歌 編曲：YOMA
Lyrics/Composition: Luca, Arrangement: YOMA
この扉の向こう側が
If the other side of this door
未開の可能性ならば
is an unexplored possibility,
今を動かせるの
then I can move the present.
暗闇を手探りで
Groping in the dark
不安と焦燥の中
amidst anxiety and impatience,
こぼれる光を見た
I saw a spilling light.
手を伸ばして
Reaching out my hand,
この先は君のものだから
because the future belongs to you.
遠い記憶を超えて
Beyond distant memories,
繋がるよ心が今
our hearts connect now.
想像するのは私のストーリー
What I imagine is my story.
声を聞かせて君を知りたいから
Let me hear your voice because I want to know you.
輝かせよう新しい世界
Let's make a new world shine.
生まれた意味を見つけるのさ
We'll find the meaning of our birth.
すべてが始まるこの場所で
In this place where everything begins,
声が枯れるまで叫んで
shout until your voice runs dry.
言葉に傷付けられ
Being hurt by words,
悲しみがこぼれるのは
and having sadness spill over,
弱いからじゃないよ
it's not because you're weak.
勇気はここにあるから
Because courage is right here,
かき消されちゃだめなんだ
it must not be drowned out.
君は君のままでいい
You are fine just the way you are.
声を上げて
Raising our voices,
私たちの歌は壊れない
our song will not break.
何度だって
No matter how many times,
伝えるよ心を今
I'll convey my heart now.
共鳴するのは私のストーリー
What resonates is my story.
名前を呼んで側にいるから
Call my name, for I am by your side.
音を奏でよう新しい世界
Let's play the sound of a new world.
君に出会うために生きていくんだ
I live on to meet you.
この場所が奇跡だから
Because this place is a miracle.
リアルを超えて繋ぐよさあ
Beyond reality, I'll connect us, come on.
夜は深く眠りに落ちて
The night falls deep into sleep,
やがて光が世界を照らすよ
and eventually, light illuminates the world.
君と出会えたこと意味を見つけたのさ
I found the meaning in meeting you.
共に分かち合って生きたい
I want to live sharing it with you.
想像するのは私のストーリー
What I imagine is my story.
声を聞かせて君を知りたいから
Let me hear your voice because I want to know you.
開拓するのは新しい世界
What I pioneer is a new world.
嘘じゃないんだ君とのストーリー
It's not a lie, my story with you.
すべてが始まるこの場所で
In this place where everything begins,
歌を歌い続けるよ
I will continue to sing my song.
今日はAZKi活動4周年ライブに
Today, for AZKi's 4th Anniversary Live,
みんな来てくれてありがとう！
thank you everyone for coming!
新しいAZKiになってもよろしくお願いします。
Please continue to support me even as the new AZKi.
また会いましょう、AZKiでした！
Let's meet again, this was AZKi!
AZKi 新ビジュアルお披露目
22.11.15. 20:00~
AZKi New Visual Reveal
4th Anniversary Live "Pages"
AZKi 新ビジュアルお披露目
22.11.15. 20:00~
4th Anniversary Live "Pages"
AZKi New Visual Reveal
Nov 15, 2022, 20:00~